Senior Software Engineer

Senior software engineer with strong web-oriented experience backed-up by a solid career in Server development. Industry experience includes Car Sharing and Online Marketing in Toronto as well as 5 years in Financial Business and 6 years in Avionics Industry for the finest European companies.

- 12 years of experience in software development and management in OOP
- Able to lead teams and manage/create entire projects from scratch
- Dedicated and self-motivated, fast learner, rigorous methodology and quality coding
- Design and manage scalable and solid IT system
- Excellent communication and presentation skills
- Bilingual English-French

Area of expertise:

Languages:	PHP/MVC, P	ython, XML,	C/C++, Java,	JavaScript, JQ	Query, HTML/CSS, Ajax
------------------------------	------------	-------------	--------------	----------------	-----------------------

• <u>IDE</u>: PHPStorm, NetBeans, Eclipse, Visual Studio, Android Studio

Environments: Windows, Linux, Unix, LAMP/WAMP, Android
 VCS: Git, Tortoise SVN, Beanstalk, CVS, Clearcase

• <u>RDBMS</u>: MS SQL, MySQL, T-SQL, PostgreSQL, Oracle, PHPMAdmin, Apache

Project Manag^t: Basecamp, MS Project, Gant project, Outlook, Lotus, Jira, Office
 Documentation: Balsamiq, Functional, Design and Test documents, Mockups
 Methodologies: Agile/SCRUM, Waterfall/V-cycle, SDLC, TDD, UML2

• Quality: DO178B (level B and C)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer

June 2013 – November 2013

Metavera, Toronto, ON, http://www.metavera.com/

With more than 50 clients all over the world, **Metavera** is the leader in car sharing system solutions for independent car share operators.

- Designed, Developed and Maintained new features and services (log system, curl, vehicle technology, etc.)
- PCI compliant environment
- Team Lead for the design and development of the Android Application

<u>Environment</u>: PHP/MVC, PHPUnit, PostgreSQL, Javascript/JQuery, HTML/CSS, Java, Android, Netbeans, Android Studio, PHPStorm, Git/Github, Windows, Linux, Agile/SCRUM, LAMP

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Project Manager/Team Lead (Online Marketing)

January 2013 – May 2013

Ploose Inc., Toronto, ON, http://www.ploose.com/

Ploose Inc. is one of the three major online marketing companies in the USA and in the world.

LMS is the main Lead Management System used by the top five lawyer companies in the USA in Social Security application. It is a web-oriented service.

- Gathered information and requirements from the sales, CTO and CEO
- Wrote requirement specifications and design documents
- Design MySQL database and PHP MVC framework
- Led and Managed a three developer team over several projects
- Was in charge of cost study, charges estimation, work breakdown and deadlines

<u>Environment</u>: PHP/MVC, PHPUnit, Javascript/JQuery, Ajax, HTML/CSS, MySQL, PHPMAdmin, Netbeans, Project management/Basecamp, Tortoise SVN/Beanstalk, Apache, Windows, Linux, Agile, LAMP

Team Lead (Financial Website)

July 2009 – June 2012

BNP Paribas, Paris, France, http://www.bnpparibas.com/, Global 500 (rank 30)

EXOCET Software is in charge of pricing, publishing and trading exotic securities on GECD secondary market. User teams are producing a nine-digit profit each year. Worldwide users (mainly traders).

- Managed Website projects, from initiating to closing
- Designed, developed and tested software add-ons and upgrades
- Managed quality with coding rules, code reviews, testing and bug tracking
- Trained and managed new website developers

Environment: PHP/MVC, PHPUnit, Javascript/JQuery, Ajax, HTML/CSS, C/C++, Transact-SQL/MS SQL Server, Project management, MSProject, SVN, Windows, Linux, Agile

Team Lead (Financial Application)

August 2008 – March 2009

SIEMENS, Seine-Saint-Denis, France, <u>www.siemens.com/</u>, Global 500 (rank 47)

EDITIQUE is the software in charge of billing's transmission all over the world.

- Debugged and restored to normal the transmission of over 2M€'s bill
- Designed software architecture
- Initiated project's quality: coding rules, CMS, testing protocol
- Trained new developer and wrote user and developer's manuals

Environment: C++, Windows, Linux, Oracle, SDLC, TDD

Senior Software Developer (Finance)

August 2007 – July 2008

Société Generale, Paris-La-Defense, France, http://www.societegenerale.com/, Global 500 (rank 62)

RTGEN is the financial market's connector for orders and data stream. It is used by high-frequency algorithms to arbitrate GECD's markets and by front office traders.

- Managed IT projects, six market's connectors
- Developed, updated and debugged new connectors
- Wrote high-level requirements and test programs
- Produced technical support level 2 for trading activity

Environment: C++, Visual Studio, CVS, UNIX, Linux, Windows, Oracle, SDLC

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Project Manager/Team Lead (Avionics)

March 2006 - July 2007

SAFRAN, Massy, France, http://www.safran-group.com/, CAC40 Company, 60K employees, 12B€ revenue in 2011

CARNAC is the main software for airport's ground beacons' calibration. It is currently used in several countries all over the world.

- Wrote high-level specifications, UML diagrams and test programs
- Designed and developed software packages
- Supervised packages integration, tests and deliveries

Environment: C++, Eclipse, UML, CVS, Linux, DO178B, SDLC, TDD

LGMS is the Landing Gear Monitoring System for the Airbus A380.

- Wrote high-level requirements, UML specifications and test documentations
- Developed and upgraded software
- Integrated and tested complete software

Environment: C, Source Insight, Perforce, MACS2/PowerPC, UNIX, DO178B, hard real-time computing, SDLC, TDD

Senior Software Developer (Avionics)

July 2004 – February 2006

THALES, Osny/Bagneux, France, http://www.thalesgroup.com/, CAC40 Company, 70K employees, 13B€ revenue in 2011

TATM is the simulator of the latest and finest helicopter for French and German army.

- Finalized developments and bug tracking/corrections
- Merged workspaces and branches to continuously produce versions
- Tested and deployed complete software versions
- Managed project's tools and CMS

Environment: C++, Python/XML, Clearcase, Windows/Unix/Linux, shell, SDLC

SYS-V projects revolve around radar-based software.

- Developed, tested and delivered a configurable system for radar tests
- Developed load analyzer software for radar signal processing

Environment: Python/XML, PHP, HTML, CSS, shell, CVS, LAMP (Linux, Apache, MySQL, PHP), SDLC

Software Developer (Biometric)

July 2001 - June 2004

SAFRAN, Eragny, France, http://www.safran-group.com/, CAC40 Company, 60K employees, 12B€ revenue in 2011

AFIS is the world's most used system for finger print recognition system.

- Developed and tested the AFIS for several countries all over the world.
- Managed site's deployment and user's support

Environment: Python/XML, Unix/Windows, Oracle, Continuus, TDD

FORMAL EDUCATION AND PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Android Application Development Ryerson University, Toronto, ON	2013
SQL tuning and optimization ORSYS, Paris, France	2010
Project management AMC TRAINING, Paris, France	April 2009 – June 2009
Fundamentals of Financial Markets FIRST FINANCE, Paris, France	2008
UML analysis and conception VALTECH TRAINING, Paris, France	2007
Java, Advanced programming ORSYS, Paris, France	2006
.NET Fundamentals with C# ORSYS, Paris, France	2005
Master's degree in Electronics, specialized in Digital Signal Processing ENSERG, Engineering school, Grenoble, France	1998 - 2001